Hsin-Tsung Chen

SUMMARY

As a data analyst with a strong background in pharmacology and drug development, I possess extensive experience in *in vivo*, *in vitro* studies, and data analysis. I am a DPhil candidate in Pharmacology at the University of Oxford, currently focusing on behaviour assessments in drug development for Niemann-Pick diseases. I also completed a Master of Research in Clinical Drug Development at University College London, where I optimized AAV9-based gene therapy for Niemann-Pick disease.

Email: hsinchen112@gmail.com Mobile: 07568086018

EDUCATION

DPhil candidate, Pharmacology, University Oxford, UK. (Oct 2018 – expecting Apr 2023)

■ Thesis: Evaluation of Gene combination therapy to Niemann-Pick disease and Behaviour assessment. (Publication in progress)

Master of Research, Clinical Drug Development, University College London, UK. (Sep 2017- Sep 2018)

■ Thesis: Design and evaluation of viral vectors with ubiquitous promoters for their use in gene therapy for Paediatric neurological disorders.

Bachelor of Science in Pharmacy, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan (Sep 2008 – June 2013)

■ Honour degree: 1st Class Honour

<u>PHARMACOLOGY EXPERIENCE</u>

- The Platt Laboratory, Oxford:
 - o Developed a novel statistical methodology for assessing mice's gait behaviours in R platform.
 - In vitro skills: cell culture, qPCR, flow cytometry, west blotting, confocal microscopy and HPLC (GSLs, Cholesterol)
 - o *In vivo* skills: behavioural assessments (gait, rotarod and open field) feeding, injection, daily care of mice and immunohistochemistry.
- The Rahim Laboratory, UCL:
 - Optimized AAV9-based gene therapy for Niemann-Pick disease.
 - Skills: cloning, (including bacterial transformation, plasmid amplification and purification) vector design.
- The Lan Laboratory, CMU:
 - o Analytical chemistry in Natural Herbs Analysis: HPCL and mass spectrometry.

DATA ANALYSIS EXPERIENCE

- Developed a novel statistical methodology, which reduced analysis time frame from 6 months to 2 weeks through a self-developed methodology for a listed pharmaceutical company, and in doing so assisted the Company in FDA Drug Approval application.
- Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate (Oct 2022)

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Obtained Oxford-Taiwan Scholarship, a fully funded scholarship awarded only to 5 Taiwanese Students per annum
- Dean research prize nomination, University College London, UK
- Completed Drug Design Course at the University of South California, CA, US (Jul-Aug 2011)
- Completed the certificate in Chinese medicine (herbal medicine)
- The team leader of two university clubs with total members in excess of 200.

PUBLICATION

Investigating the Mechanism of Cyclodextrins in the Treatment of Niemann-Pick Disease Type C Using Crosslinked 2-Hydroxypropyl-β-cyclodextrin

Carradori, Dario; Chen, Hsintsung; Werner, Beat; Shah, Aagam S.; Leonardi, Chiara; Usuelli, Mattia; Mezzenga, Raffaele; Platt, Frances; Leroux, Jean-Christophe Small, November 2020, Vol.16(46), pp.n/a-n/a

EXPERIENCE

Pharmaceutical caretaker, Taiwan Foundation For Rare Disorders, UK and EU. (Sep-Oct 2017)

First-hand experience following a family with Niemann-Pick Type-C disease.

Provided European equivalent medication information while travelling.

Learned how to care for the patient in this condition and utilised disabled step-free access in the UK and mainland Europe.

Pharmacist at Ten-Chen hospital, Taoyuan, Taiwan (Jul-Aug 2017)

Dispensed prescriptions, pointed out drug-drug interaction and adjusted dose and formula on prescriptions which were suspected to be erroneous.

Pharmacy assistant, Watsons pharmacy, London, UK (Nov 2016- Jul 2017)

Over The Counter products selling, stock management, and basic medical consulting. This position gave me a chance to serve customers with professional knowledge.

Non-Pharmaceutical working experiences, London, UK (Dec 2015- Oct 2016)

Receptionist and Sales assistant.

Developed communication, teamwork, and IT (Word, Excel, Email) skills.

Community pharmacist, Taichung, Taiwan, (Oct 2014-Oct 2015)

Dispensed prescriptions and provided medical information to patients.

Accommodated a wide variety of patients. Significantly improved soft skills.

Second lieutenant, the R.O.C army, Kaohsiung, Taiwan (October 2013- September 2014)

Translator between Singapore and R.O.C army in a combined military exercise.

As a military officer, I have learnt how to organise a team efficiently.

Summer Intern, Pfizer, Taipei, Taiwan (July-August 2012)

Visited customers with sales in hospitals and community pharmacies.

Formulated an annual marketing plan with product manager assistance.

Improved marketing skills with real experience of sales.

<u>OTHER EXPERIENCE - LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES</u>

Academic Student Representative, UCL, UK (Sep 2017 – Sep 2018)

Negotiation skills, communication skills and summary skills.

Head of Medical Community Service Team 2008-2012

Raised public health awareness via campaigns and lectures in various places, including juvenile detention centres and daytime care centres.

Lead a team of around 200 to win the annual best Service Team at the university in 2012.

Club president of calligraphy club 2008-2012

Reviving the club which was on the brink of closure by increasing members by more than tenfold, making it the fifth largest society within the university. Held the first calligraphy competition in the university with over 40 participants.